Visual AIDS Artist Files
Visual AIDS Archive
- Richard Sawdon-Smith (b. 1963)
  Richard Sawdon Smith first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2004. They contain artwork on postcards, a CV, correspondence, slide lists, an artist's statement, exhibition announcements, periodicals, publications, photographic prints, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1990-2012.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/richard-sawdon-smith
  - Box 52, Folder 3 (Box 52)
  - Box B, Folder 15 (Box B)
- Peter Schepper (b. 1964)
  Peter Schepper was born in 1964 in Albany, New York. He studied fine art and theatre at Texas State University and Del Mar College. His work includes painting, sculpture, collage, pen and ink drawing, and puppetry. It has been exhibited in New York.
  Peter Schepper first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2010. They contain Postcards from the Edge submission materials, exhibition announcements, an image list, a CV, correspondence, and artwork. These materials are dated 2009-2011.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/peter-m.-schepper-pms
  - Box 52, Folder 4 (Box 52)
- Hal Scheppner (d. 2003)
  Hal Scheppner's art included quilting, watercolor, and oil painting. He passed away in 2003.
  Materials pertaining to Hal Scheppner were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 2004 by Georgianne Scheppner. They contain correspondence and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 2001-2005.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/hal-scheppner
  - Box 52, Folder 5 (Box 52)
- Adrienne Seed (b. 1947)
  Adrienne Seed was born in 1949 in England. She received a BA in fine art from St Martin's University in London. Her work includes painting and sculpture. Her work has been exhibited internationally and is held in a number of private collections.
  Adrienne Seed first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2009. They contain a CD with images of art, correspondence, a CV, an image list, a publication, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image lists. These materials are dated 1969-2009.
  - Box 52, Folder 8 (Box 52)
- Andreas Senser (1942–1989)
  Andreas Senser was born in 1942 in Saint-Gallen, Switzerland. He travelled through the UK where he studied painting, watercolor technique, and education. He worked as a painting therapist in France. From 1973 to his death, he lived between New York and Paris, making collaged paper structures and paintings. He passed away in 1989.
  Materials pertaining to Andreas Senser were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998 by Sur Rodney (Sur). They contain Postcards from the Edge submission materials, publications of artwork, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1982-1992.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/andreas-senser
  - Box 53, Folder 1 (Box 53)
- Donna Sewell (b. 1962)
  Donna Sewell was born in 1962 in California. She studied at Chabot Jr College in Hayward, California. In addition to making art, she also spends time teaching art to disabled children.
  Donna Sewell first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2002. They contain an artist's biography and an artist's statement. These materials are dated 2002.
  - Box 53, Folder 2 (Box 53)
- Michael Sharkey (b. 1948)
  Michael Sharkey was born in 1948 in Queens, New York. He received an associates degree in advertising design and a BA in fine arts. He worked in advertising for over 20 years. In 1997 he began to exhibit and sell his paintings. His paintings are inspired by impressionist art.
  Michael Sharkey first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2002. They contain Postcards from the Edge submission materials, exhibition announcements, artist's biographies, artist's statements, photocopies of personal photographs, photocopies of photographs of art, and 35mm slide documentation with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1998-2012.
  - Box 53, Folder 3 (Box 53)
- Tom Shooter (1941–2004)
  Tom Shooter was born in 1941 in Williamsport, Pennsylvania. He received a BFA from Tufts University, and both an MA and MFA from the School of the Museum of Fine Arts in Boston. He taught painting and painted prolifically for many years. His work was exhibited widely in Massachusetts as well as New York, DC, Pennsylvania, Connecticut, and Italy. He passed away in 2004.
  Tom Shooter first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2001. They contain exhibition catalogs, exhibition announcements, memorial materials, CVs, artist's statements, journal excerpts, photocopies of artwork, press releases, image lists, press clippings, photographic prints, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image lists. These materials are dated 1975-2004.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/tom-shooter
  - Box 53, Folder 6 (Box 53)
  - Box 53, Folder 7 (Box 53)
- Tracy Karl Silverberg (1966–2005)
  Tracy Karl Silverberg was born in 1966 in Houston, Texas. He studied theatre, communications, journalism, advertising, and photography. His work is primarily in black and white photography. It has been exhibited in Texas and Georgia. He passed away in 2005.
  Tracy Karl Silverberg first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2005. They contain a CV, an artist's biography, an artist's statement, a death certificate, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 2004-2005.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/tracy-silverberg
  - Box 54, Folder 1 (Box 54)
- James "Jimmie Mack" Simmonds (1948–2008)
  James "Jimmie Mack" Simmonds was born in 1948 in Wahoo, Nebraska and lived in Omaha for most of his life. He was a self-taught artist who used weaving and found materials to create "spirit baskets". His work was inspired by his grandmother Jose, an Iowa Sioux, who taught him how to weave baskets. His work was exhibited in Nebraska. He passed away in 2008.
  James "Jimmie Mack" Simmonds first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2001. They contain Postcards from the Edge submission materials, correspondence, newsletters, artist's biographies, artist's statements, articles, image lists, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 2000-2006.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/james-jimmie-mack-simmonds
  - Box 54, Folder 2 (Box 54)
- Ted Singer (b. 1957)
  Ted Singer was born in 1957 in Patterson, New Jersey. His work includes illustration and collage.
  Ted Singer first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2000. They contain an artist's biography and correspondence. These materials are dated 2000.
  - Box 54, Folder 3 (Box 54)
- Ron Singleton (b. 1958)
  Ron Singleton was born in 1958 in Detroit, Michigan. He is a self-taught photographer who began to pursue photography after 15 years in law. His work has appeared in various queer publications and has been exhibited in California and New York.
  Ron Singleton first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2001. They contain a CV, an artist's biography, an artist's statement, and an exhibition announcement. These materials are dated 2001.
  - Box 54, Folder 5 (Box 54)
- Michael Slocum (1956–1995)
  Michael Slocum was born in 1956. He was a comic artist, writer, activist, and editor of People with AIDS Coalition Newsline, a monthly magazine. His comic "Zander Alexander, PWA" appeared in Newsline from 1993 until his death in 1995.
  Materials pertaining to Michael Slocum were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain exhibition announcements, copies of PWAC Newsline, ephemera, an artist's biography, a curator's statement, copies of comics illustrations, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1993-2021.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/michael-slocum
  - Box 54, Folder 6 (Box 54)
- Clifford Smith (b. 1955)
  Clifford Smith was born in 1955 in Havelock, North Carolina and grew up in Michigan and Southern California. In the late 1970s and 80s he was a professional dancer. In the 1990s he taught himself art and began making hand-woven creations and other mixed media work, which took inspiration from mandalas.
  Clifford Smith first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1999. They contain a CD with images of art, ephemera, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, photographic prints, exhibition announcements, a marriage announcement, a book of poetry, exhibition programs, artist's statements, correspondence, image lists, calendar submission materials, press release, artist's biographies, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1995-2016.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/clifford-d.-smith
  - Box 54, Folder 8 (Box 54)
  - Box 54, Folder 9 (Box 54)
  - Box 54, Folder 10 (Box 54)
- Jack Smith (1932–1989)
  Jack Smith was born in 1932. He lived and worked in New York from the 1950s until his death. He was a filmmaker, actor, and pioneer of underground cinema. He is generally acclaimed as a founding father of American performance art. His influence extends across photography and experimental theatre as well. He passed away in 1989.
  Materials pertaining to Jack Smith donated to the Visual AIDS archive contain exhibition announcements, ephemera, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1996-2014.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/jack-smith
  - Box 55, Folder 1 (Box 55)
- Huck Snyder (1954–1993)
  Huck Snyder was born in 1954 in Lansdale, Pennsylvania. He studied at the College of William and Mary in Virginia and the Goethe Institute in Berlin. He was a visual artist and a designer of vivid stage settings for dancers and performance artists. His work was surrealist and imaginative. His work has been displayed widely in the US, Europe, and Japan, and has won many awards. He passed away in 1993.
  Materials pertaining to Huck Snyder includes an undated artist's biography.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/huck-snyder
  - Box 55, Folder 2 (Box 55)
- Thomas R. Somerville (b. 1960)
  Thomas R. Somerville was born in 1960 in Rochester, New York. He studied at San Diego City College and received a BS, an MS in painting and poetry, and an MS in art education from Rochester Institute of Technology. His paintings have been featured in various publications and exhibited in California and New York and one of his pieces traveled the country in the Share Your Vision exhibition.
  Thomas R. Somerville first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2003. They contain artwork on postcards, ephemera, a calendar with artwork, books with photographs of artwork, exhibition catalog, correspondence, press clippings, an exhibition announcements, CVs, artist's statements, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 2002-2010.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/thomas-somerville
  - Box 55, Folder 3 (Box 55)
- Harry Soviak (1935–1984)
  Harry Soviak was born in 1935 in Lorain, Ohio. He received both bachelors and masters degrees in painting from Cranbrook Academy of Art in Bloomfield Hills, Michigan. He taught painting and drawing in Haiti for a time, and later moved to New York City, working in the textile industry. He worked at the Philadelphia College of the Arts in various capacities until his death. His paintings were exhibited widely across the US. He passed away in 1984.
  Materials pertaining to Harry Soviak donated to the Visual AIDS archive contain ephemera, photographs of artwork, exhibition materials, correspondence, exhibition catalogs, a CV, and curatorial statements. These materials are dated 1985-1996.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/harry-soviak
  - Box 55, Folder 5 (Box 55)
- Matti Kniva Spencer (b. 1952)
  Matti Kniva Spencer was born in 1952 in Lewiston, Maine. He received a BS in education from the University of Maine. He worked as a preschool teacher for 13 years before switching to human service work. He was a photographer from a young age and began pursuing professional photography in 2000. His work has been exhibited in Massachusetts.
  Matti Kniva Spencer first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2003. They contain Postcards from the Edge submission materials, photographic prints, correspondence, press clippings, exhibition announcements, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 2003-2019.
  - Box 55, Folder 7 (Box 55)
- David Spiher (b. 1958)
  David Spiher was born in 1958 in Washington, DC. He received a BFA from Indiana University and an MFA from Ohio State University. His work spans illustration and painting, as well as hand-painted ceramic plates. He lives and works in Hawai'i.
  David Spiher first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain exhibition announcements, correspondence, CDs with images of art, CVs, image lists, calendar submission materials, press clippings, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1992-2006.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/david-spiher
  - Box 55, Folder 8 (Box 55)
- Joseph Stabilito (b. 1955)
  Joseph Stabilito was born in 1955. He studied at Tyler College of Art, the Art Institute of Philadelphia, and the School of Visual Arts in New York. His paintings are made with layers of acrylic paint, creating bold images. His work has been exhibited in New York, Chicago, and internationally.
  Joseph Stabilito first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1997. They contain correspondence, images of art, artist's statements, CVs, image lists, calendar submission materials, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1995-2003.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/joseph-stabilito
  - Box 55, Folder 9 (Box 55)
- Maxime Angel Starling (b. 1977)
  Maxime Angel was born in 1977 in Rome, Italy. Her work includes large-scale mixed media collage and performance work. She began performing after moving to London in the late 1990s. Her work has been exhibited in Berlin and London.
  Materials pertaining to Maxime Angel Starling include a copy of an undated online publication.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/maxime-angel-starling
  - Box 55, Folder 11 (Box 55)
- Mike Stead (b. 1976)
  Mike Stead was born in 1976 in Hartlepool, England and grew up in various countries including Germany, China, and Thailand. He was educated at Edinburgh College of Art and Cleveland College of Art and Design. His work spans painting and printmaking as well as graphic novels. His work has been exhibited widely in England and in the US.
  Mike Stead first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2012. They contain artist's statements and CVs. These materials are dated 2012.
  - Box 56, Folder 2 (Box 56)
- Hugh Steers (1962–1995)
  Hugh Steers was born in 1962 in Washington, DC. He studied art at Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture, Yale University, and Parsons School of Design. His figurative paintings worked to capture the emotional and political tenor of New York in the 1980s and 90s. His work was exhibited widely in New York and across the US. He passed away in 1995 in New York City.
  Materials pertaining to Hugh Steers were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998 by Jay Swanson. They contain a CD with images of art, memorial materials, exhibition announcements, correspondence, proposals, artist's statements, CVs, bibliographies, inventories, writing about artist, press clippings, press releases, schedules, photocopies of personal materials, photographic prints of art, eulogies, exhibition catalogs, periodicals, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1990-2016.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/hugh-steers
  - Box 56, Folder 3 (Box 56)
  - Box 56, Folder 4 (Box 56)
  - Box 56, Folder 5 (Box 56)
- Patric Stillman (b. 1962)
  Patric Stillman was born in 1962 in Shakopee, Minnesota. He works primarily in painting and he is known for his Radical Faerie-themed Brotherhood Tarot. His work has been exhibited internationally and appeared in various publications. He lives and works in San Diego, California.
  Materials pertaining to Patric Stillman donated to the Visual AIDS archive contain a CD with images of art and an exhibition announcement. These materials are dated 2017.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/patric-stillman
  - Box 56, Folder 7 (Box 56)
- Juan C. Suazo (b. 1963)
  Juan C. Suazo was born in 1963 in San Juan, Puerto Rico. His work spans sculpture and craft, particularly the creation of masks. His art has been exhibited in New York.
  Juan C. Suazo first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2011. They contain a CD with images of art with accompanying image list, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, an exhibition announcement, ephemera, and press releases. These materials are dated 2007-2013.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/juan-suazo
  - Box 56, Folder 8 (Box 56)
- Gekoo Surlee/Zagul (b. 1968)
  Gekoo Surlee was born in 1968 in North Pond, Nusantara in Indonesia. He moved to New York in 1998. His work includes oil, watercolor, and acrylic painting, as well as mixed media work incorporating recycled materials. His work was exhibited in Nusantara and New York.
  Gekoo Surlee first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain correspondence, an artist's biography, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1998.
  - Box 56, Folder 10 (Box 56)
- JD Talasek (b. 1966)
  JD Talasek was born in 1966 in Dallas, Texas. He received a BS from East Texas State University and an MFA from the University of Delaware. He also studied at the Prague School of Photographic Studies. His work is primarily in photography and has been exhibited and published widely across the US.
  JD Talasek first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain correspondence, ephemera, exhibition announcements, CVs, press releases, press clippings, artist's statements, calendar submission materials, artist's biographies, publications, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1998-2003.
  - Box 57, Folder 2 (Box 57)
  - Box C, Folder 1 (Box C)
- Tim Tate (b. 1960)
  Tim Tate was born in 1960 in Washington, DC. He works primarily in sculpture and glasswork. He co-founded the Washington Glass School and his work has been shown nationally and internationally since the 1990s. His work is also held in permanent collections around the US.
  Tim Tate first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2006. They contain a CV, an image list, a periodical, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 2005-2007.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/tim-tate
  - Box 57, Folder 4 (Box 57)
- Luis Tavales (b. 1958)
  Luis Tavales was born in 1958 in Queens, New York. He is a self-taught artist working in painting and digital arts. His work has been exhibited in New York.
  Luis Tavales first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2010. They contain Postcards from the Edge submission materials, correspondence, ephemera, CDs with images of art, exhibition announcements, artist's biographies, CVs, and image lists. These materials are dated 2008-2012.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/luis-tavales
  - Box 57, Folder 5 (Box 57)
- Steed Taylor (b. 1959)
  Steed Taylor was born in 1959 in Cumberland County, North Carolina. He received a BA in English and studio art from the University of North Carolina and an MBA in marketing from American University. He also studied at the Skowhegan School for Painting and Sculpture. His art practice spans public art projects as well as work for gallery settings, including painting, photography, sculpture, and more. His art has been exhibited widely in the US. He has also worked in AIDS activism for many years. He lives and works in New York.
  Steed Taylor first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1997. They contain Postcards from the Edge submission materials, ephemera, exhibition announcements, correspondence, photobooks of art, artist's statements, press releases, press clippings, CVs, publications, calendar submission materials, photocopies of art, image lists, exhibition materials, portfolios, periodicals, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying slide list. These materials are dated 1964-2013.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/steed-taylor
  - Box 57, Folder 6 (Box 57)
  - Box 57, Folder 7 (Box 57)
  - Box 58, Folder 1 (Box 58)
- Tom Teebe (b. 1946)
  Tom Teebe was born in 1946 in Brooklyn, New York. He studied at the American Academy of Dramatic Arts. He also studied drawing and oil painting at the 92nd St Y. He works primarily in portraiture, using oil, pastel, conte, and charcoal. His work has been exhibited in New York.
  Tom Teebe first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1999. They contain correspondence, ephemera, photographs of art, artist's biographies, an artist's statement, calendar submission materials, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1998-2001.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/tom-teebe
  - Box 58, Folder 2 (Box 58)
- Joey Terrill (b. 1955)
  Joey Terrill was born in 1955 in Los Angeles, California. He studied at Immaculate Heart College and Cal State University Los Angeles. He draws inspiration from cartoons, comics, magazines, pop culture, and artistic movements of the 1950s and 60s. His art is often related to his activism around AIDS and Chicano social justice efforts. His work has been exhibited widely in California and New York.
  Joey Terrill first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2007. They contain exhibition announcements, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, ephemera, press clippings, CVs, artist's statements, image lists, copies of zines, exhibition catalogs, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1988-2023.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/joey-terrill
  - Box 58, Folder 3 (Box 58)
  - Box C, Folder 6 (Box C)
- Paul Thek (1933–1988)
  Paul Thek was born in 1933 in Brooklyn, New York. He studied at Pratt Institute, the Art Students League, and Cooper Union. Though he began as a painter, he became known for his sculptures and installations. His work has been exhibited widely internationally and remains in various permanent collections. He passed away in 1988.
  Materials pertaining to Paul Thek were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 1997 by Ted Bonin. They contain exhibition announcements, CVs, press clippings, press releases, scans of journal pages and illustration, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1964-2011.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/paul-thek
  - Box 58, Folder 4 (Box 58)
  - Box C, Folder 2 (Box C)
- Keith Theriot (b. 1960)
  Keith Theriot was born in 1960 in Louisiana. He received a BFA from Louisiana State University. His work includes painting and mixed media and has been exhibited widely across the US.
  Keith Theriot first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2004. They contain exhibition announcements, correspondence, ephemera, a CD with images of art, an image list, CVs, artist's statements, press clippings, periodicals, and photographs of artwork. These materials are dated 2004-2008.
  - Box 58, Folder 5 (Box 58)
  - Box C, Folder 3 (Box C)
- Michael Tidmus (1951-2012)
  Michael Tidmus was born in 1951 in Toronto, Canada. He works primarily in painting and digital art. His art has been exhibited across California, New York, and elsewhere in the US. He taught photography and computer graphics in California. He passed away in 2012.
  Michael Tidmus first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2008. They contain a CV, an article, correspondence, and images of artwork. These materials are dated 1993-2008.
  - Box 58, Folder 6 (Box 58)
- TRET Tierney (b. 1960)
  Thomas TRET Tierney was born in 1960 in the Bronx, New York. He was received a BFA from Pratt Institute. His work includes photography, collage, and mixed media work and has been exhibited widely in New York.